First of all, we make this look easy.
Us black girls with all kinds of curls
smelling the cocoa butter out here
every damn day saving the world.
Time and time again, we find the ways and means
between packing lunches, planning launches,
and patting weaves to get information to save information.
Girl, you heard what they saying?
Ain't no games to be playing.
So we show up and show out and turn up and turn
this mother out and flip it and yasmin'.
Throw side eyes, gather, get folks all the way together
with edges still in place, skin-defying time and space.
They call it black girl magic
because ain't no way to explain our amazing grace.
Sound of a black girl's point of view.
Knowing that nobody does it like we do, boo.
Pride in our power, strengthen our strides.
You can attempt to imitate, but soul, you cannot buy.
We work twice as hard and must be twice as perfect.
Purveyors of potent truths we deliver in small doses
because folks is shook when she's moving.
Oh no, it's another.
Bump that.
We're not hostile.
We're passionate.
Clapping back is our way of declaring
we ain't having it.
They go low, we go high.
They say no, we defy.
They didn't want us to read.
Kept us out of libraries they built.
Now we are the biggest buyers of books
so we can read you for filth.
Our magic is in our love and tears,
our fears and our flyness,
our sisterhoods and insecurities,
our ride or don't even try yet.
We are not the one and still we rise.
This here is for colored girls
who've considered getting your life
and are reclaiming our time.
Thank you.